shopalltel.com 2008-06-12

# Shop Alltel

This Privacy Policy last updated on: 06/29/2007

Alltel has created this privacy statement ("Policy") to communicate our privacy practices and policies. This privacy statement outlines what information we collect, use, disclose, and how we protect such information when you access or use any of our services. Alltel may revise or update this Policy from time to time, so you should refer back to this page often for the latest information. 

What is "personally identifiable information" and how does it relate to me?  
What is "customer proprietary network information" (CPNI)?  
When and how is information collected?  
How does Alltel use "personally identifiable information"?  
Will my "personal information" be disclosed?  
How does Alltel support the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act?  
How secure is my information?  
What about links to other websites?  
What are value-added services?  
Will this privacy policy be updated in the future?  
How can I contact Alltel?

 **What is "personally identifiable information" (PII) and how does it relate to me?**  
Personally identifiable information is information that is directly associated with a specific person such as a subscriber's name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, and location information. . 

Alltel does not consider “aggregate” information to be personally identifiable information. Aggregate information is data we collect about a group or category of services or customers from which individual customer identities have been removed. For example, we may combine your information with information about how other customers use the same service, with no personally identifiable information included in the resulting data. Aggregate data helps us identify trends and customer desires so that we can consider new services or enhance existing services to better meet customer needs.

**What is "customer proprietary network information" (CPNI)?**  
Certain information is made available to Alltel solely by virtue of a customer’s relationship with us. Under U.S. federal law, customers have a right and we have a duty to protect the confidentiality of information that relates to their usage of our services and the type of services they purchase from us. This information is known as Customer Proprietary Network Information, CPNI. Specifically, CPNI is information that relates to the quantity, technical configuration, type, destination, location, and amount of use of the telecommunications services a customer purchases from Alltel. 

Except as permitted by law or with customer approval, Alltel will only use, disclose, or permit access to the CPNI it receives or obtains by virtue of its provision of telecommunications service in connection with (a) marketing service offerings from within the category of service the customer subscribes, or (b) services necessary to providing telecommunications service, such as, but not limited to, billing, provisioning, and collecting payments.

**When and how is information collected?**  
We collect personal information in a variety of ways: 

**Information you give us:** We collect information you give us when you purchase or use Alltel products and services, or request information about our services. For example, you provide us with your billing address and credit information when you purchase service from us. Similarly, you may provide personal information when you submit a job application. 

**Automatically collected information:** We automatically receive certain types of information whenever you interact with us. When your phone is turned on, wireless systems know your network location and your approximate physical location, which is how calls or information are delivered to you.

**Information from other sources:** We may receive information about you from other sources. For example, we receive credit information from third-party sources before initiating service you have requested. We may add such information or combine it with personal information on your account.

**How does Alltel use personal information?**  
We collect, maintain, and use customers’ personal information as necessary to provide the most helpful and targeted products and services to meet customers’ needs. We also use personal information for billing purposes, marketing new and existing services, resolving service problems, and enhancing customer relationships. In addition, we use personal information to evaluate employment qualifications and communicate with job applicants.. 

**Will my personal information be disclosed?**  
Alltel does NOT sell personal information and we disclose personal information only in the following ways: 

  1. **With your consent**  
We may obtain your consent to disclose personal information in a number ways, including in writing; verbally; online by clicking a button; entering information on a wireless device or handset; or at the time of initiation or use of any service when your consent is part of the required terms and conditions to use the service. Other times your consent is implicit. For example, if you purchase a product through our Web site and request that it be shipped to your home, you implicitly consent to our disclosure of your name and address to ship your order and also of your charge card number to the bank to collect payment and complete your order.. 
  2. **Transaction processing**  
We disclose personal information to third parties as necessary to complete transactions or perform services on our behalf. Alltel must share some private information with our contractors, consultants, and other parties who require such information to assist us to establish, maintain, and manage our business relationships with customers.

Alltel may let you take advantage of services and products offered by other companies. In those cases, information about you received by those third parties will be managed by those third parties. For example, if you use your phone and roam on the network of another carrier, your usage information and the numbers you dial will be available to the company providing that service. Also, when you purchase a product from a third party through an Alltel service, you may provide personal information to that entity and some information may automatically be passed to that entity. 

  3. **Certain business transfers**  
Customer personal information may be transferred as part of various business transactions, such as mergers and acquisitions, insolvency, bankruptcy or receivership, in support of the transaction.
  4. **Protection of Alltel and others**  
We release personal information, other account information, and possibly location information (as discussed below in 5. Location-based Services) when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law (e.g., subpoenas, court orders, E911 information); to enforce or apply our customer agreements; to initiate, render, bill, and collect for services; or to protect Alltel’s rights or property, or to protect users of those services and other carriers from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful use of, or subscription to, such services; or if we reasonably believe that an emergency involving immediate danger of death or serious physical harm to any person requires disclosure of communications or justifies disclosure of records to a governmental entity without delay.
  5. **Location-based Services**  
Alltel provides wireless location-based services that use your wireless network location to provide services you request. Whenever your mobile device is on, the network knows its general location. Customers should be mindful that their wireless network location is necessary to be able to provide these services, and that it is solely at the customer’s discretion to subscribe to location-based services..

It is important to note, if you let others use location-based services to which you’ve subscribed as the account holder (or if you let others use your handset if such handset has location tracking capabilities), it is your responsibility to inform that user that his or her location may be tracked.

When you dial 911 for emergency services, we may provide your network location to an emergency medical service provider or emergency dispatch provider, public safety answering point, or other emergency services provider. The law also permits us to disclose the location of a device on our network without a user’s consent to managers or providers of information services solely for the purposes of assisting in the delivery of emergency services in response to an emergency, or to emergency service providers in order to respond to the user’s call for emergency services. 

**How does Alltel support the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA)?**  
Alltel does not intend for its products or services to collect personal information from children under the age of 13 years. We believe that parents should supervise their children’s on-line activities to ensure that no information is collected from a child under the age of 13 years without parental permission. If a child under the age of 13 years has provided personal information without the consent of a parent or guardian, that parent or guardian should [contact us](http://www.alltel.com/contact_us.html) if they wish that information be deleted from our records. More information about parental controls is available [here](http://www.alltel.com/personal/cs/parental_controls.html). Additionally, we understand that wireless devices and services purchased for family use may be used by minors without the knowledge of Alltel; if that happens, any information collected from the usage will appear to be the personal information of the actual adult customer and will be treated as such by Alltel. 

**How secure is my information?**  
Alltel maintains a variety of physical, technical, and procedural safeguards to guard your personal information. We have security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of information under our control. 

We limit access to personal information to those employees, contractors, consultants, and other parties who require such information to assist us with establishing, maintaining, and managing our business relationship with our customers. These parties may provide services to us or on our behalf or they may collaborate with Alltel in providing services to our customers..

**What about links to other websites?**  
Many Alltel websites, including wireless (WAP) websites, contain links to other websites that are not owned, operated, or otherwise controlled by Alltel. You should be aware that we have no control over the security of such other sites on the Internet you visit, interact with, or from which you may buy products or services. Alltel is not responsible for content or privacy policies of other sites. You should keep this in mind when accessing sites through links on Alltel’s website. 

**What are value-added services?**  
Because we appreciate the trust you have placed in us, we continually look for ways to enhance our business relationship. So from time to time, we may let you know about a product or service. We may inform you about products and services by email, short text messages, telemarketing, and direct mail. Using the information you have provided to us, we strive to limit our offers to those we think you would appreciate receiving. We want every contact you have with us to be a positive experience. So if you would prefer not to receive these value-added services, offers and opportunities, just [contact us](http://www.alltel.com/contact_us.html). 

**Will this privacy policy be updated in the future?**  
As with all Alltel sites, we will constantly strive to improve the services we may offer, and may update this privacy policy from time to time in connection with that effort. You should refer back to this page often for the latest information. 

**How can I contact Alltel?**  
If you have any questions, comments or concerns about Alltel's Privacy Policy, please contact [Office.of.Privacy@alltel.com](mailto:Office.of.Privacy@alltel.com). If you have questions about your account, your service, our products, etc., please contact a [Customer Care Representative](http://www.alltel.com/contact_us.html).
